# TRINADH KOYA

- @ trinadhkoya9@gmail.co m
- h 099-667-77479
- a Hyderabad, TG 500001 https://github.com/trinadhkoya

#### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

A self-starter with 4+ years of experience in Software Field. Have a good passion for learning new technologies and motivated to accept challenges in Programming. I have an ability to adapt the design quickly and code for the same. Keeping Professional standards make my code beautiful. Always take my work as my asset so I love to decorate it.

# SKILLS

- Languages: Java, Python ,JS
- UI: : HTML, CSS, JS
- Framework: React Nativ e, Redux, Django, Sprin g, Hibernate(Beginner)
- Android development
- Programming
- Research and Developm ent

# **EDUCATION**

Jawaharlal Nehru Techn ological University Kakinada, AP • 05/2014

Bachelor's: Information T echnology

Graduated with 7.0 GPA

# **WORK HISTORY**

Tinmen - Senior Software Engineer Hyderabad, Telangana • 11/2018 - Current

- Revamped existing mobile app built on an ionic framework to React Native
- Responsible for setting up the architecture for mobile apps using React Native, Redux, Redux-Thunk
- Design React Native components and higher-order components which keeps the project easy to understand
- Worked closely with the project management and marketing team to completely define specifications to help ensure project acceptance
- Responsible for delivering mobile apps to their corresponding stores and keep an eye on customer feedback on the store
- Wrote redux code in a separate library which can be accessed from a single source of truth for both mobile and web
- Wrote own library for Instagram-stories transition which was not open-sourced yet

Zaggle Prepaid Ocean Services Pvt. Ltd - React Native Developer Hyderabad, Telangana • 04/2017 - 11/2018

- Revamped the existing mobile apps built on Native Platforms to React Native
- Responsible for setting up the architecture for mobile apps using React Native, Redux, Redux-Thunk
- Worked closely with the project management and marketing team to completely define specifications to help ensure project acceptance
- Responsible for delivering mobile apps to their corresponding stores and keep an eye on customer feedback on the store
- Wrote redux code in a separate library which can be accessed from a single source of truth for both mobile and web
- Developed a Native Module which provides communication between the user and customer support team with the help of FreshChat APIS, as there is no library available

Dotlabs Web Solutions - Android Developer *Hyderabad*, *Telangana* • 03/2015 - 04/2017 Ask The Doctor, in short ATD, is a healthcare first opinion platform which enables the user(Patient) to engage doctors via Email/Chat/Video/Phone. Apart from that, we enable Enroute option like Uber, to get connected with the doctor for major things. We make use of OpenTok for our communication like Video, Chat, Phone.

- Worked closely with customers to constantly innovate app functionality and design
- Keeping up to date with the terminology, concepts and best practices for coding mobile applications
- Support the entire application lifecycle (concept, design, test, release, and support)
- Gather specific requirements and suggest solutions. Research and suggest new mobile products, applications, and protocols.

# PUBLIC ARTIFACTS

react-native-stories:
A React Native component to create

Instagram/Snapchat like stories on the mobile. It supports both Android and iOS. It provides control over the story duration and loading indicator with cubic transition similar to Instagram.

https://github.com/Amit-khatkar/react-native-stories
react-native-boilerplate:

A React Native project template for building solid applications through the separation of concerns between the UI, state management and business logic.

https://github.com/trinadhkoya/react-nativeboilerplate

react-native-spinner:

A React Native component to create Airbnb like progress bar on the mobile. A React Native component to create Instagram/Snapchat like stories on the mobile.

https://github.com/trinadhkoya/react-native-spinner

# WORK REFERENCES

#### Tinmen:

- https://apps.apple.com/in/app/tinmen/id1069990797
- Https://play.google.com/store /apps/details?id=com.vicinia.tinmen&hl=en\_IN

# Zaggle:

- https://play.google.com/store /apps/details?id=com.zaggle&hl=en\_IN
- https://apps.apple.com/in/app/zaggle /id1030365320